所以我要给你们看一个小的，一种欺骗的方式，去找库伯内特。
So I'm gonna show you a little, kind
of cheat way, to get on to Kubernetes.
我们要用一个叫 Kompose的项目
And we're gonna use
a project called Kompose.
跟 K 一起
Kompose with a K.
所以回到我们的项目 Kompose
So coming back over to our project here,
Kompose.
我要你在 Kompose 上点击
I want you to click here on Kompose,
which is kompose.io.
这是 Kubernetes 组织的一个正式项目，它是
This is an official project from the
Kubernetes organization, which is part of
我认为它是 Linux 基金会的一部分。
the Cloud Native Foundation, which I
believe is part of the Linux Foundation.
好了我想让你进来
Okay, and
then I want you to come in here and
我想那里有个安装标签
I think there is
an installation tab right there.
这是另一个您要下载并运行的 curl 命令。
And it's another curl command that
you're gonna download and run.
就在那就是你想要的那个
And right there,
that's the one that you want.
你要做同样的歌舞曲和舞蹈
You're gonna have to do
the same kinda song and dance,
让它执行一个小小的加 X 然后把它移动到你的道路上
make it execute a little plus X,
and then move that into your path.
看起来它也会在 Windows 上工作。
And it looks like it will
work on Windows as well.
看起来我们有一个二进制文件从 GitHub 安装。
It looks like we have a binary
that you just install from GitHub.
但我觉得你被困在了 PowerShell 的土地上
But again,
I think you're stuck in PowerShell land.
好的。
Okay.
现在我有了 Kompose
So now that I have Kompose.
这只是版本
It's just version.
给你，我有 1.19， 1.19。
There you go, I have 1.19, 1.19.
我们需要做的一件事是我们需要修改我们的码头
And the next thing that we need to do is
we need to go modify our docker-compose
用一点时间来处理这个问题
file a little bit to work with this.
这就是组成你的工作的原因是它需要的是 Docker 编写的文件
So that's what compose does for you,
is it takes the docker-compose file that
我们把它变成了库伯内特的构造
we wrote, and it turns that into
a Kubernetes configuration.
这挺酷的因为文档的编写很容易
Which is pretty cool,
because docker-compose is pretty easy by
与 Kubernettes 配置的比较。
comparison to understand to
Kubernetes configurations.
只要我们能构建好的 Docker-编写我们可以使用的文件
So as long as we're good building
Docker-compose files we can be using
库伯内特
Kubernetes.
你能做的和我个人做的事
And what you can do and what I do
personally, when I'm messing around with
Kubernetes I将从 Docker 编写文件开始，我将使用编写
Kubernetes I'll start with
the Docker-compose file, I'll use compose
把所有东西都转换成 Kubernetes 的输出然后我就从那儿走了
to convert everything to Kubernetes
output and then I'll go from there.
好了我们要去我们的码头了
Okay, so we're gonna come
into our docker-compose.yml.
我们要改变形象
We're gonna change the image or
因为它不会为我们建立一个形象
the build to an image because
it won't do builds for us.
这件事对你和库伯内特不会有任何的
That's one thing that compose will
not do for you nor Kubernetes.
因此，一旦您将此更改为 btholt/node-app ，那么会出现在 Docker Bub上，
So once you change this to
btholt/node-app, so this is on Docker Bub,
这就是我们一直在构建的应用
it's literally the app that we've
been building this whole time.
我刚刚构建它并将其推送到 Docker Hub ，以便我们能够做到这一点，但是
I just built it and pushed it to
Docker Hub so that we can do this, but
你得通过一个注册中心
you have to go through a registry.
因此，是在本地运行您自己的注册表还是将其推送到
So whether that's running your own
registry locally or that's pushing it to
Git Hub 软件包存储库，或将其推送到 Docker Hub 或 Azure 容器注册表。
a Git Hub package repository or pushing it
to Docker Hub or Azure Container Registry.
有一堆地方你可以推这些
There's a bunch of different
places you can push these.
现在我们只能使用 Docker Hub ，因为这是最简单的。
For now we're just gonna use Docker Hub
because that's the easiest one.
好了 3000口
Okay, ports 3000.
由于您不使用 Kubernetes ，因此我们将除去此卷部分
And we are gonna get rid of this volumes
part because you do not use Kubernetes for
发展目的。
development purposes.
所以这些东西都是不有用的
So that's all this stuff is not useful.
如果你像我一样把港口送回去，那是 3000 : 3000。
When I put ports back if you took that
out like I did, which is 3000:3000.
链接 db ，那就好，环境，
Links db, that's fine, environment,
那就好了，我们得加添一个，就是标签。
that's fine, we gotta add one more though,
which is labels.
所以库伯内特必须知道我们的
So there's certain things that
Kubernetes needs to know about our
特定服务。
particular service.
其中之一就是这是负载均衡服务
And one of them is that this
is a load balancing service,
这意味着它需要像在它前面的负载均衡器一样。
which means that it needs to have like
some sort of load balancer in front of it.
所以如果你想让 10 个容器同时运行库伯内特也可以
So if you wanna have ten containers
running at the same time Kubernetes can do
我们的负载平衡
that load balancing for us.
因此 Docker 组成没有内置的负载均衡概念。
So Docker compose doesn't have this
concept of load balancing built into it.
所以我们得说几个话
So we have to kind of
indicate to compose like hey,
请将其放入 Kubernetes 负载均衡情况。
please put this into the Kubernetes
load balancing situation.
所以你说 compose.service.type 和
So you say compose.service.type, and
你就说这是负载均衡器
you just say this is a load balancer.
因此，标签通常用于诸如数据库容器之类的内容。
So labels are typically more used for
things like, this is a database container.
然后，通过您的集群定义的内容，可以方便地搜索。
And then it makes it easy for like search
through your clusters defined things.
他们只是在这个意义上的标签。
They're just labels in that sense.
好吧最后一件事我们得给
Okay, and
last thing here on we have to give
要使用的数据库显式端口。
the database explicit ports to be using.
所以我们要把这个放在 27017上
So we're gonna say please
put this on 27017.
好了，现在我们有了这个 Docker 合成文件的组合。
Okay, so now we've kind of
composified this Docker compose file.
好吧好吧
All right.
所以我想指出的一件事就是我们做了这个
So the one thing that I wanted to
point out to you is we did this
负载均衡器在这里
load balancer thing right here.
如果你试着把它推到亚马逊或者 Azure 之类的地方
If you try and push this to something
like Amazon or to Azure, they know how to
来吧负载均衡器他们为你建了服务
deal with it, load balancers,
they have built in services for you.
通常，它们不便宜。
Typically, they're not cheap.
所以如果你有 15 种不同的服务它们都是负载均衡器
So if you have like 15 different services,
and they're all load balancers,
很快就会很贵的
that's gonna get really
expensive really quick.
你真正想做的事
What you're actually gonna wanna to do for
大多数情况下，您的服务中的每一个都不会负载均衡。
the most part is not have each one
of your services be load balanced.
你想把 NGINX 之类的东西都在前面
You're gonna wanna have something
like NGINX in front of everything in
所有事物的负载均衡
that load balances across everything.
所以就知道了，我不希望有人像我那样叫我
So just be aware of that, I don't want
someone to call me with like I had
我要杀了你我要杀了你
a $10,000 bill and
I'm going to kill you, please don't.
我在 Kompose里面放了个好纸条
I put a nice note in here
inside of the Kompose.
在哪儿
Where is it?
来自 Google 云解释负载均衡器的博客帖子。
A great blog post from Google Cloud
explaining load balancer.
还有一个叫 NodePort的东西
There's another thing called NodePort,
就好像在每个人的港口都暴露了一样东西
which is just like exposes
the same thing on everyone's port.
就像我说在 3000 港曝光会暴露在里面的每个容器里
So like if I say expose on Port 3000,
it'll be exposed on every container inside
在我的集群中， 3000 端口将是一个容器。
of my clusters,
Port 3000 will be that one container.
你还可以使用 LoadBalancer ，还有一个叫做 Ingress的东西。
And you can also use LoadBalancer and
there's another thing called Ingress.
出口不一定是一回事，只是一个想法，就像 NGINX，对吧 ?
Ingress is not necessarily a thing, it's
just an idea, which is like NGINX, right?
使 NGINX 管理所有进入特定集群的入口流量。
Having NGINX manage all of your Ingress
traffic into your particular cluster.
一个你不需要知道的大话题
Kind of a deep topic you don't really
need to know this is gonna work for
我们的发展环境
our development environment.
好吧我需要你做个类似的黑客攻击
All right, so
I need you to do like kind of a hack here,
这就是 Kompose 如何运作的问题
this is for
how Kompose is expected to work.
我得去找你的工作了
It needs someway to talk to your kubectl.
所以你要运行这个 kubectl 代理 --port-8080。
So you're gonna run this
kubectl proxy --port-8080.
而且它只会开始服务进口的交通
And it's just gonna start
serving traffic imported.
我想你可以看看它吧
You can actually take a look at it,
I think.
如果我记错的话就没什么好刺激的了
It's nothing exciting,
if I remember correctly.
是啊，基本上是 API 让任何人都能与您的多维数据集进行交互，对吧 ?
Yeah, it's basically an API for anyone to
interact with your cube control, right?
这让你的电脑暴露了
It's kind of exposing that
to your local computer.
好吧我不想在前台运行
Okay, so
I don't wanna run that in the foreground.
你可以说如果我把它放在最后
You can actually just say,
if I put &amp; here at the end,
它会在后台运行
it's gonna run it in the background.
所以现在如果我看我的电脑，我显然有很多东西，所以
So now if I look at my computer,
which I obviously have a lot of things, so
如果我做了希腊的草皮你可以在这里看到它在这里的背景下运行
if I do ps aux grep kubectl, you can see
here, it's running here in the background.
这就是最终的结果，它的最终目的就是把事情变成背景。
That's what that end, does it the end
is it forces stuff into the background.
你可以像屏幕和 T Max 那样
You can do that with like screen and
T Max and
一堆其他的东西只会偷懒别用这个
a bunch of other stuff to just lazy and
don't use this.
好了现在该开始了
All right, so now that's running, and
如果你不这样做就不会有办法了
this won't work by the way
if you don't do that.
既然我们有了小公子我们会说的
So now that we have kompose,
we're gonna say kompose up.
你可以在这里看到它创建了一个数据库服务，它创建了一个网络服务，
And you can see here it create a db
service, it created a web service,
它为这两个和
it created a deployment for
both of these and
所有内容都在缺省名称空间中运行。
everything's running in
the default name space.
理论上，我们应该可以来这里说当地的 3000 人。
So in theory, we should be able to
come here and say local host 3000.
现在它在库伯内特的内部工作。
And it's working now within Kubernetes.
非常酷，你现在在计算机上运行一个 Kubernetes 集群。
So pretty cool, you are now running
a Kubernetes cluster on your computer.
我觉得很酷，就很困难，
Which I find to be very cool,
like this is very difficult and
花了很多时间让它变得这么简单
it's spent a bunch of time getting
it down to be this simple.
所以我需要你做个该死的人就像我需要你那样做
So I need you to be dammit,
like I need you do the impressed by this.
让我们来看看在车篷下面到底发生了什么。
So let's take a look at what's actually
happening underneath the hood.
所以如果我说 kubectl ，请大家，你可以看到，我有这个部署，
So if I say kubectl, get all,
You can see here, I have this deployment,
这个部署出去了，我还有复制集，我有一些 ClusterIP。
this deployment going out, and I have
replicasets going, I have some ClusterIPs.
但我最感兴趣的部分是服务，对吧 ?
But the part that I'm actually most
interested in is the services, right?
我有个服务数据库我有个网站服务
I have a service for db,
I have a service for web,
这个是 LoadBalancer ，这个只是一些静态 IP。
this one is a LoadBalancer,
this one is just some static IPs.
在这种情况下，您的 ClusterIP，记住这些是内部集群 IP。
And in this case, your ClusterIPs, keep
in mind these are internal ClusterIPs.
所以如果我想这样做就不行了
So if I tried like ping this,
it wouldn't work,
因为这只会在它的虚拟网络里工作
because this only works inside of
Kubernetes, inside of its virtual network.
但是这个有一个外部 IP ，它是在端口 3000 上暴露一个 localhost 。
But this one does have an external-IP,
is it's exposing a localhost on port 3000.